# Muralidhar S

+91-9902116457

murali4lp@gmail.com

https://murali4lp.github.io

# **SUMMARY**

I have 12+ years of experience in the IT industry having worked with clients in Technology, Retail and pharmaceutical industries. I have expertise in product development, program management, product management, full stack development, consulting, change management and data science.

I have completed my MBA from IIM Indore and prior to my MBA, I have worked as a Software Engineer developing Java based Middleware & BPM software solutions

# **SKILLS**

#### **Functional Skills**

- Product Development
- Program Management
- Product Management
- Data Science
- Consulting
- Change Management

## **Technical Skills**

- Angular (2+)
- NodeJS
- MongoDB
- Express
- HTML, CSS, Javascript
- Java, SQL

## **EXPERIENCE**

Product Developer, Bootstrapping Tech Entrepreneur

JAN 2018 - PRESENT

- Ideated, designed and developed products (Progressive Web Apps) shown below
- <u>Visnory</u> a web based online solution for creating stories through animated cartoons

#### **Product Features**

- o Drag-Drop Solution
- User Collaboration
- Scene Creation
- Object Animation
- Access Control
- Story Versioning

- Multiple Stories
- Timeline Control
- BGM Addition
- Camera Effects
- Video Conversion

 <u>Senixa</u> - a custom Business Intelligence Dashboard builder SaaS solution. Explainer videos on what Senixa <u>does</u> and how it <u>works</u>

#### **Product Features**

Customizable

Charts

Multiple Data

Source Types

Hierarchical Access

Control

- MultipleDashboards
- o Edit & Published

Versions

User Collaboration

- Both products are currently in beta. The end to end solution development was a solo effort. I have used MEAN Tech stack to develop both the products
- Note: Product demos require test user accounts and can be given, if required.

# Cognizant Business Consulting (CBC), Bangalore - Senior Consultant

Client - A leading search, internet and technology giant

**Role - Program Management, Product Management** 

APR 2014 - DEC 2017

- Global Tools (web and mobile) POC of the team that managed a
  global Feet on Street business data (listings) acquisition program for
  the client's mapping and related local data products. 5M+ business
  listings and 12M+ photos directly added as a result of the program.
- **Closely collaborated** with multiple stakeholders Engineering, mapping products teams, cross functional teams, operations, policy, training to drive program execution and program initiatives.
- Streamlined program processes by setting up a global team for managing issue escalation, testing and application releases for the suite of mobile apps and web applications used in the program.
   Reduced issue resolution and app rollout times by an average 50%.
- Assessed, identified and prioritized engineering requirements
  backlog based on business impact and program roadmap. Eliminated
  15-20% of issues in the overall backlog which were false alarms or had
  process/policy workarounds.
- Defined, led and executed several pilots in collaboration with cross functional teams. Cross functional teams were able to collect field data, pilot new products and test hypotheses on the field leveraging the program infrastructure.
- Defined, executed, evaluated and validated a joint initiative of the Feet on Street program with another program that combined both field and backend operations. This reduced the operational costs by 30%.
- Led and executed the global transformational initiative to implement and manage change in process, tools, policy and training in the successful global transition of the standalone Feet on Street program to the client's overall Local Business Data Org. The client was able to

- achieve a great degree of operational efficiencies and reduce costs by **25**% through **standardization in tools, processes and policies**.
- Identified, developed and monitored program performance metrics through several business intelligence dashboards. Successfully transitioned the metrics tracking and reporting process to a dedicated reporting & analytics team.

# Cognizant Business Consulting (CBC), Bangalore - Consultant

Client - A leading software, technology and consumer electronics giant Role - Consulting

MAR 2013 - APR 2014

- Enabled solution delivery by collaborating with client teams, solution
  delivery teams to develop use cases, process maps and requirements
  documentation for a customized BI reporting solution for the client's
  extended warranty service & technical support solution.
- Developed the below project artefacts and set up a knowledge sharing platform to enable collaboration and knowledge sharing between solution delivery teams.
  - Process maps of as-is and to-be processes for a project related to the Taxation & Invoicing regulatory compliance of the client's sale of digital products and services in Brazil.
  - Use case maps and user requirements documentation for a project related to the client's custom web CMS solution.
  - Use case documents, process blueprints, RTM documents for custom projects in the client's online music service and contact support service systems.

## Cognizant Business Consulting (CBC), Chennai - Consultant

Client - A leading luxury retailer Role - Process Consulting

APR 2012 - DEC 2012

- **Enhanced team knowledge base** of the client systems and processes by solution delivery teams by developing process blueprints of the client's SCM business processes and IT application landscape.
- **Enabled greater collaboration** between solution delivery teams by consolidating, standardizing & organizing the Knowledge Management repositories and defining processes for asset management..

# **Cognizant Technology Solutions (CTS), Bangalore** - Associate

Client - A Leading Pharmaceutical company

Role - Middleware Software Development, Project Management

AUG 2006 - JUN 2010

- Led a team of 3 offshore developers in solution development & deployment of BPM and middleware solutions to handle master data changes in the client's ERP applications.
- Collaborated with client and onsite teams in requirements management, effort estimation, Issues tracking, stakeholder coordination, project scheduling.
- Collaborated with global teams in China, US, Argentina to ensure on schedule solution development, process compliance, software quality assurance, delivery and continuity.
- Proposed and implemented a middleware solution integrating the purchase order management system with the client ERP system that reduced the overall solution delivery time by 70%.
- Successfully delivered a critical middleware solution for BI & analytics applications on schedule under exceptional circumstances and reduced project costs by 50%.

## **EDUCATION**

Indian Institute of Management, Indore - MBA

JUN 2010 - MAR 2012

JSS Academy Of Technical Education, Bangalore - Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Electronics and Communications
SEP 2002 - JUN 2006

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

**AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate** - *Amazon Web Services* 2020

**John Hopkins University** - Coursera Data Science Specialization 2015

# **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Power to the People: Customer Care and Social Media

A POV addressing some of the major challenges of customer care operations on social media

# **AWARDS**

**Consulting Achievers Award** - CBC

# **Exceptional Project Execution - "Outstanding Performer" - CBC**

Q1 2016

"Going the Extra Mile" (GEM) - CBC

Q4 2015

Advisor Excellence in Thought Leadership - CBC

Q3 2015

**Dream Team - CBC** 

Q1 2014

Enterprise Application Integration (EAI) Star Performer - CTS

Q2 2008

# **ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS**

- IIM Indore Campus Champion and National Finalist of TAS TATA Business Leadership Awards (TBLA).
- IIM Indore Campus Champion and National Finalist of ITC
   Interrobang, a b-school case study competition organized by ITC.
- IIM Indore Campus Champion of Veet- Brand Extensions, a b-school case study competition in Marketing strategy organized by FMS and Reckitt Benckiser.
- **IIM Indore Campus Finalist** out of 156 teams that participated in Mahindra War room, an all India business strategy competition.
- **Secured the highest marks** in Class XII examination in a batch of more than 250 students in BHSFGC, Bangalore.